Guide to the Jeh Vincent Johnson Papers, 1917-2020 (bulk 1945-2004)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Jeh Vincent Johnson Papers
1917-2010
1945-2004
Johnson, Jeh Vincent, 1931-
48 cubic feet (15 boxes, 138 roll boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The Jeh Vincent Johnson Papers contain materials created or collected by Johnson throughout his life and career as an architect and Vassar College faculty member.
Biographical Note
Jeh Vincent Johnson was an American architect and professor. Born in Nashville, Tennessee in 1931 to Marie Antoinette (Burgette) Johnson (1891-1965) and Charles Spurgeon Johnson (1893-1956), Johnson grew up on the campus of Fisk University, where his father taught Sociology, and later became its first African-American president. Johnson attended Columbia College and graduated with his B.A. in 1953 before being drafted into the U.S. Army for almost two years. After returning from service, he married Norma Edelin, the sister of his college roommate, Milton Edelin and returned to Columbia University to pursue his Master's in Architecture, which he received in 1958. After a short period working with acclaimed architect Paul R. Williams, and several years working for as a designer for Adams and Woodbridge Architects in New York City, Johnson relocated to the Hudson Valley in 1963 and joined the practice of practice of William Gindele (1925-2020) as an associate.
In 1964, Johnson began teaching at Vassar College as a lecturer, and in 1968, became a full partner with Gindele, creating Gindele & Johnson, PC Architects. In 1971, Johnson and several colleagues at the American Institute of Architects national convention in Detroit formed the National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA). Johnson designed numerous buildings in Dutchess County, New York, particularly in Poughkeepsie. Buildings designed by Johnson include: the Vassar College Intercultural Center (now the Jeh V. Johnson ALANA Cultural Center), the Catharine Street Community Center, Central Baptist Church of Poughkeepsie, Tubman Terrace Apartments, Ebenezer Baptist Church, Poughkeepsie YMCA, and Saint Simeon Senior Citizens Apartments. Johnson also designed many renovations, rehabilitations, and additions to existing buildings, including hundreds of private residences. He taught at Vassar until his retirement in 2001. Johnson and his wife Norma had two children: Jeh Charles Johnson (1957-) and Marguerite Marie Johnson (1959-2020).
He died in 2021 at the age of 89.
Scope and Content Note
The Jeh Vincent Johnson Papers contain materials created or collected by Johnson throughout his life and career as an architect and Vassar College faculty member. Materials include correspondence with friends, family, colleagues, and other corporate and government entities; records of his architectural jobs and the architectural firms he was associated with, including building specifications, photographs, sketches, architectural plans, financial records, and legal documents; and records of his teaching career at Vassar College, such as correspondence with students and course planning materials. Also included are various personal and professional papers, such as writings and drawings, professional organizations, family memorabilia, audio reels, and research subject files.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into nine series: Series I. Correspondence; Series II. Professional Papers; Series III. Artwork and Writing; Series IV. Subject Files; Series V. Vassar College; Series VI. Personal and Family Papers; Series VII. Photographic Materials; Series VIII. Audio Reels; and Series IX. Plans.
Access
Certain materials in this collection are restricted until 2035, including early diaries, family correspondence, and correspondence with current and former students. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Biographical Files
Vassar College Facilities Operations Records
Subject Headings
Names:
Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, 1893-1956; Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, 1921-; Johnson, Jeh Charles, 1957-; Johnson, Jeh Vincent, 1931-; Johnson, Marie Antoinette Burgette, 1892-1965
Organizations:
American Institute of Architects; Columbia University; National Organization of Minority Architects (U.S.); Vassar College
Subjects:
African American architects; African American architects—United States; African American architecture; African American churches; Architecture--Study and teaching; Architecture, Domestic—Designs and plans; Architecture, Domestic--United States; Minorities in architecture—United States; Minority-owned architectural firms—United States; Teachers, Black--New York (State)
Places:
Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)
Document Types:
Architectural drawings (visual works); Audiovisual materials; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Diaries; Drawings (visual works); Financial records; Floor plans (orthographic projections); Notes (documents); Photographs; Plans (orthographic projections); Printed ephemera; Site plans; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Slides (photographs); Specifications
VCL Categories:
African Americans; Art and Artists; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, September 2025.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Jeh Charles Johnson, acting under power of attorney for Norma (Edelin) Johnson, 2024. (M2024-011, M2024-020)
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1945-2020; (Box 1)
  This series contains correspondence to and from Jeh V. Johnson with family, friends, colleagues, corporate entities, and branches of the United States Government. Correspondence with family members and close friends is restricted until 2035.
  Organized into two subseries: Outgoing Correspondence (from Jeh V. Johnson) and Incoming Correspondence (to Jeh V. Johnson). Arranged alphabetically within each subseries.
- Series II. Professional Papers, 1948-2015; (Boxes 1-3, 12)
  This series contains records of Jeh V. Johnson's architectural work and engagement with professional organizations, including the American Institute of Architects (AIA) and National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA). Johnson's architectural work includes work he performed as an independent architect, as well as work done during his time at Gindele & Johnson, Architects, and LeGendre, Johnson, & McNeil. These records include newsletters, correspondence, building specifications and sketches, legal documents, project lists, financial records, and conference materials.
  Arranged alphabetically by file title.
- Series III. Artwork and Writing, circa 1940-2013; (Boxes 3-5, 10-11, 13-14)
  This series contains Jeh V. Johnson's writings and drawings, both personal and professional. Materials include diaries, notebooks, sketches, sketchbooks, travel "road notes, and college papers, as well as drafts and clippings of various articles and other writings.
- Series IV. Subject Files, 1953-2014; (Boxes 5-6)
  This series contains Jeh V. Johnson's subject files on topics of interest, including: Africa-American churches, Black architects, Fisk University, and historic buildings.
- Series V. Vassar College, 1964-2018; (Boxes 6 and 10)
  This series contains records related to Jeh V. Johnson's career as a lecturer in architecture at Vassar College. Includes departmental records, correspondence, course planning materials, notes on Vassar graduates pursuing careers in architecture, and correspondence with current and former students. Correspondence with students is restricted until 2035.
- Series VI. Personal and Family Papers, 1917-2015; (Boxes 6-7, 11, 13, 15)
  This series contains materials related to Jeh V. Johnson's family and personal life, including clippings and printed ephemera related to life events and achievements; certificates and awards; financial records; and high school and college materials.
- Series VII. Photographic Materials, circa 1955 - [2010?]; (Boxes 7-9)
  This series consists of photographs, negatives, and slides, primarily of Jeh V. Johnson's architectural jobs, his classes and students at Vassar, as well as his trips around North America and Europe.
  Organized into two subseries by format: Photographs and Slides. Arranged alphabetically by file title within each subseries.
- Series VIII. Audio Reels, 1962, undated; (Box 9)
- Series IX. Plans, 1950-2005; (Roll Boxes 1-138)
  This series contains architectural plans and sketches for buildings and other structures designed, renovated, or updated by Jeh V. Johnson or the architectural firms he worked for.
  Organized into six subseries by building type or affiliation: Churches, Commercial and Community Buildings, Multi-Unit Residences, Single-Unit Residences, Vassar College Buildings, and Miscellaneous and Unidentified Buildings. Arranged alphabetically by name or title within each subseries.
Container List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1945-2020
  - Outgoing (from Jeh V. Johnson)
    - Bond, Max, 1969 (Folder 1.1)
    - Eastwood, Alan, 1990 (Folder 1.2)
    - Johnson, Charles S., Jr. (brother of Jeh V. Johnson), 1979, 1993; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.3)
    - Johnson, Jeh Charles (son of Jeh V. Johnson), 1993 (Folder 1.4)
    - Johnson, Marie B. (mother of Jeh V. Johnson), 1957; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.5)
    - Williams, Paul R., 1970 (Folder 1.6)
    - Others, 1974-1977 (Folder 1.7)
    - Others, 1982-1983, undated (Folder 1.8)
  - Incoming (to Jeh V. Johnson)
    - "A" General, 1957-1983 (Folder 1.9)
    - The American Institute of Architects (AIA), 1963-1983 (Folder 1.10)
    - The American Institute of Architects, New York Chapter, 1958-1972 (Folder 1.11)
    - "B" General, 1952-1993 (Folder 1.12)
    - Bridges, Leon, 1983 (Folder 1.13)
    - Browne, Sandra, 1977-1990; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.14)
    - "C" General, 1956-2013, undated (Folder 1.15)
    - Clifford, Patricia Johnson (sister of Jeh V. Johnson), 1945-1993; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.16)
    - Columbia University, 1953-1982 (Folder 1.17)
    - "D" General, 1946-1993 (Folder 1.18)
    - Demond, Antoinette S., 1956-1980; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.19)
    - "E-F" General, 1954-2009 (Folder 1.20)
    - Edelin, B. G. (Norma's father), 1957-1958; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.21)
    - Edelin, Kenneth (Norma's brother), 1957, 1976; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.22)
    - Edelin, Milton (Norma's brother), 1955-1981; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.23)
    - Edelin, Yvonne, 1979-1993; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.24)
    - "G" General, 1949-2020 (Folder 1.25)
    - "H" General, 1952-2001 (Folder 1.26)
    - Hoopes, David S., 1954-1958 (Folder 1.27)
    - [Howard?], Mary, undated (Folder 1.28)
    - Hyde, James H., 1949-1956 (Folder 1.29)
    - "J" General, 1952-2002 (Folder 1.30)
    - Johnson, Charles S. (father of Jeh V. Johnson), 1945-1950; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.31)
    - Johnson, Charles S., 1951-1953; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.32)
    - Johnson, Charles S., 1954-1956; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.33)
    - Johnson, Charles S., Jr. (brother of Jeh V. Johnson), 1946-1957; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.34)
    - Johnson, Charles S., Jr., 1973-1993; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.35)
    - Johnson, Jeh Charles (son of Jeh V. Johnson), 1972-2006; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.36)
    - Johnson, Julia and Lillie J. Epps (aunts of Jeh V. Johnson), 1954-1984; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.37)
    - Johnson, Marguerite Marie (daughter of Jeh V. Johnson), 1978-1990; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.38)
    - Johnson, Marie B. (mother of Jeh V. Johnson), 1945-1955; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.39)
    - Johnson, Marie B., 1956-1959; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.40)
    - Johnson, Norma Edelin, 1955; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.41)
    - Johnson, Norma Edelin, 1956; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.42)
    - Johnson, Norma Edelin, 1977, undated; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.43)
    - Johnson, Norma Edelin, from Others, 1955, undated; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.44)
    - Johnson, Robert "Bobby" (Brother), 1949-1956; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.45)
    - Johnson, Rosamond D. "Rosie" (sister in-law of Jeh V. Johnson), 1949-1951; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.46)
    - Johnson, Trey, 1955, 1979; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.47)
    - "K" General, 1953-1982 (Folder 1.48)
    - Kennedy, Royal, 2007-2009 (Folder 1.49)
    - "L" General, 1983 (Folder 1.50)
    - "M" General, 1956-1996 (Folder 1.51)
    - [M.?], Roger, undated (Folder 1.52)
    - McHenry, Mary, 1952-1982 (Folder 1.53)
    - Morris, Victor O., 1982-1983 (Folder 1.54)
    - "N-O" General, 1957-1983 (Folder 1.55)
    - New York State Board for Architecture, 1983 (Folder 1.56)
    - "P" General, 1975-1994 (Folder 1.57)
    - "R" General, 1945-1976 (Folder 1.58)
    - "S" General, 1956-1990 (Folder 1.59)
    - Sanders, Katrina, 1998-2001; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.60)
    - Saunders, Valerie, 1981; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.61)
    - Smith, William L. "Bill", 1953, undated; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.62)
    - Stanton, Janice D., 1952 (Folder 1.63)
    - "T" General, 1956-1988 (Folder 1.64)
    - Thackeray, Gail, 1973-1979; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.65)
    - Thornton, Ruth, 1951-1956; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 1.66)
    - Town of Poughkeepsie, 1974-1976 (Folder 1.67)
    - "U-V" General, 1974-1997 (Folder 1.68)
    - University of the State of NY, The State Education Department, 1978, 1983 (Folder 1.69)
    - "W" General, 1955-1998 (Folder 1.70)
    - The White House, 1966, 1969 (Folder 1.71)
    - Williams, Paul R., 1956, 1972 (Folder 1.72)
    - Unidentified, 1946-1955 (Folder 1.73)
    - Unidentified, 1970-1979 (Folder 1.74)
    - Unidentified, 1980-1989 (Folder 1.75)
    - Unidentified, 1990-1999 (Folder 1.76)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1.77)
- Series II. Professional Papers, 1948-2015
  - American Institute of Architects (AIA), 1992-1993 (Folder 1.78)
  - American Institute of Architects, Continuing Education, 1996-2006 (Folder 1.79)
  - Architectural Jobs - "A Country Home," renderings, 1956 (Folder 1.80)
  - Architectural Jobs - Churches, renderings, undated (Folder 1.81)
  - Architectural Jobs - Dutchess County Mental Health Center, renderings, circa 1967 (Folder 1.82)
  - Architectural Jobs - Ebenezer Baptist Church, renderings, 1992 (Folder 1.83)
  - Architectural Jobs - Ebenezer Baptist Church, specifications and renderings, 1995; [microfilm reel] (Box 12)
  - Architectural Jobs - Eleanor Roosevelt Center at Val-Kill (ERVK), 1997-2002 (Folder 1.84)
  - Architectural Jobs - Eleanor Roosevelt Center at Val-Kill (ERVK), 2003 (Folder 1.85)
  - Architectural Jobs - Eleanor Roosevelt Center at Val-Kill (ERVK), 2004 (Folder 1.86)
  - Architectural Jobs - Eleanor Roosevelt Center at Val-Kill (ERVK), "The Garage-Stable, Eleanor Roosevelt National Historic Site: Historic Structure Report", 1981 Sep (Folder 2.1)
  - Architectural Jobs - Miscellaneous buildings, 1965-1987 (Folder 2.2)
  - Architectural Jobs - Miscellaneous buildings, renderings and sketches, undated (Folder 2.3)
  - Architectural Jobs - Mt. Zion Baptist Church, church extension plans, 1995 Feb 16 (Folder 2.4)
  - Architectural Jobs - Mt. Zion Baptist Church, correspondence, specifications, and project records, 1995-1997 (Folders 2.5-2.7)
  - Architectural Jobs - Mt. Zion Baptist Church, lawsuit materials, 1996-1998 (Folder 2.8)
  - Architectural Jobs - Mt. Zion Baptist Church, preliminary plan, 1995 Jun 12 (Folder 2.9)
  - Architectural Jobs - Mt. Zion Baptist Church, requisitions, 1996 (Folder 2.10)
  - Architectural Jobs - Mt. Zion Baptist Church, specifications, 1995 May 10 (Folder 2.11)
  - Architectural Jobs - Mt. Zion Baptist Church, specifications, amended, 1996 Jan 10 (Folder 2.12)
  - Architectural Jobs - Salvation and Praise Deliverance Center, 1995-2004 (Folder 2.13)
  - Architectural Jobs - Salvation and Praise Deliverance Center, legal records, 1994-1997 (Folder 2.14)
  - Architectural Jobs - Salvation and Praise Deliverance Center, legal records, 1994-2004 (Folder 2.15)
  - Architectural Jobs - St. Anna Apartments, sprinkler specifications, 1997 (Folder 2.16)
  - Architectural Jobs - St. Simeon Senior Apartments II, renderings, circa 1991; [microfilm reel] (Box 12)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Ely Hall renovations, 1990 (Folder 2.17)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Goodfellowship House renovation, 1992-1994 (Folder 2.18)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Intercultural Center, sketches and renderings, 1991 (Folder 2.19)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Intercultural Center, specifications and renderings, 1992; [microfilm reel] (Box 12)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Metcalf House renovation, 1996 (Folder 2.20)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Poughkeepsie Day School renovations, 2000-2001 (Folders 2.21-2.22)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Pumphouse Building alterations, 1993-1995 (Folder 2.23)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Sanders Classroom renovation, 1997-2000 (Folders 2.24-2.25)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Sanders Classroom renovation, specifications, 2000 Feb 25 (Folder 2.26)
  - Architectural Jobs - Vassar College, Sanders Classroom renovation, specifications, 2000 Mar 8 (Folder 2.27)
  - Dutchess County Historic Landmarks Study, 1966 (Folder 2.28)
  - Gindele & Johnson, Architects - Brochure, circa 1971 (Folder 3.1)
  - Gindele & Johnson, Architects - Correspondence, 1971-1977 (Folder 3.2)
  - Gindele & Johnson, Architects - Project lists, 1962-2005 (Folder 3.3)
  - HRVC meeting minutes, 1968 Apr (Folder 3.4)
  - Jeh Vincent Johnson Limited, Inc. - Financial report, 1948 (Folder 3.5)
  - Job list, 1970 (Folder 3.6)
  - LeGendre, Johnson, & McNeil - Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Folder 3.7)
  - National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA) - Annual Conferences, 1982-1988 (Folder 3.8)
  - National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA) - Annual Conferences, 1990-1992 (Folder 3.9)
  - National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA) - Annual Conferences, 1994-1999 (Folder 3.10)
  - National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA) - Annual Conferences, 2001-2004 (Folder 3.11)
  - National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA) - Annual Meetings, 1974-1999 (Folder 3.12)
  - National Organization of Minority Architects (NOMA) - Annual Meetings, 2009 (Folder 3.13)
  - NOMA - General, 1971-1987 (Folder 3.14)
  - NOMA - General, 1991-2002 (Folder 3.15)
  - NOMA - List of conferences and meetings, 1997 (Folder 3.16)
  - NOMA - List of practicing Black architects, circa 1970 (Folder 3.17)
  - NOMA Magazine, 2004-2006 (Folder 3.18)
  - NOMA Magazine, 2007-2008 (Folder 3.19)
  - NOMA Member lists, 1988, 1990 (Folder 3.20)
  - NOMA Newsletter, 1982-2002 (Folder 3.21)
  - NOMA Reports, 1974-1998 (Folder 3.22)
  - Private jobs, 1963-1965 (Folder 3.23)
  - Publication - Dutchess County Planning Department, "Housing Designed to Build Neighborhoods", undated (Folder 3.24)
  - "Single-Family House Prototypes", 1988-1989 (Folders 3.25-3.26)
  - Town of Poughkeepsie Historic Commission, 2002-2003 (Folder 3.27)
  - Town of Poughkeepsie Historic Commission, 2004-2007 (Folder 3.28)
  - Town of Poughkeepsie Historic Commission, 2008-2015 (Folder 3.29)
- Series III. Artwork and Writing, circa 1940-2013
  - Architectural renderings, 1955-1956 (Folder 3.30)
  - Diary, 1950; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.1)
  - Diary, 1951; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.2)
  - Diary, 1952; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.3)
  - Diary, 1953; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.4)
  - Diary and financial ledger, 1953-1954; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.5)
  - Diary, 1955-1956; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.6)
  - Diary and financial ledger, 1955-1956; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.7)
  - Diary and financial ledger, 1956-1958; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.8)
  - Diary, 1978 Aug - 1982 Jan; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.9)
  - Diary, 1982 Mar - 1992 Apr; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.10)
  - Diary, 1992 May - 1997 Aug; [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2035] (Folder 10.11)
  - Notebook, 1952-1953 (Folder 3.31)
  - Notebook, 1959-1960 (Folder 3.32)
  - Notebook, 1963 Sep - 1966 Dec (Folder 3.33)
  - Notebook, 1966 Aug - 1969 Jan (Folder 3.34)
  - Notebook, 1969 Feb - 1973 Apr (Folder 3.35)
  - Notebook, 1978-1981 (Folder 3.36)
  - Notebook, 1981-1984 (Folder 3.37)
  - Notebook, 1981 Oct - 1983 Oct (Folder 4.1)
  - Notebook, 1983-1985 (Folder 4.2)
  - Notebook, 1985-1989 (Folder 4.3)
  - Notebook, 1987-1999 (Folder 4.4)
  - Notebook, 1991 Jul - 1993 Nov (Folder 4.5)
  - Notebook, 1994-1995 (Folder 4.6)
  - Notebook, 1997-1999 (Folder 4.7)
  - Notebook, 2001 May - 2002 Apr (Folder 4.8)
  - Notebook, 2007-2017 (Folder 4.9)
  - Notebook, 2011 Oct - 2013 Dec (Folder 4.10)
  - Notes, circa 1950 (Folder 4.11)
  - Notes, undated (Folder 4.12)
  - Notes and clippings, 1967-1995 (Folder 4.13)
  - Notes, clippings, and sketches, circa 1991 (Folder 4.14)
  - Road Notes, 1958-1959 (Folder 4.15)
  - Road Notes, 1966, 1969-1970 (Folder 4.16)
  - Road Notes, 1972 (Folder 4.17)
  - Road Notes, 1973-1978 (Folder 4.18)
  - Road Notes, 1974 (Folder 4.19)
  - Road Notes, 1987-1988 (Folder 4.20)
  - Road Notes, 1997-1999 (Folder 4.21)
  - Road Notes, 1999 Jun - 2002 May (Folder 4.22)
  - "Scaled House Plans - Uzes, Siena, Montclair, Home", undated (Folder 4.23)
  - Sketchbook, 1975-1976 (Folder 4.24)
  - Sketchbook, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
  - Sketchbook, 1977-1978 (Folder 4.25)
  - Sketchbook, 1979-1981 (Folder 4.26)
  - Sketchbook, 1988-1990 (Folder 5.1)
  - Sketchbook, 1993 Dec - 1994 Dec (Folder 5.2)
  - Sketchbook, 1995 (Folder 5.3)
  - Sketchbook, 1999-2001 (Folder 5.4)
  - Sketchbook, 2002-2009 (Folder 5.5)
  - Sketchbook, undated (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Sketches, circa 1940-1950 (Folder 5.6)
  - Sketches, circa 1970s (Folder 5.7)
  - Sketches, 1981-1994 (Folder 5.8)
  - Sketches, 1983-1994 (Folder 5.9)
  - Sketches, 1983-1997 (Folder 5.10)
  - Sketches, 1985-1997 (Folders 5.11-5.12)
  - Sketches, 1985-2000 (Folder 5.13)
  - Sketches, undated (Folders 5.14-5.15)
  - Sketches - Rob / Millbrook House, 1997 (Folder 5.16)
  - Writings - "An Approach to the Development of Prototypes in Housing", circa 1970s (Folder 5.17)
  - Writings - "An Autobiography of Summer Experiences", 1948 (Folder 5.18)
  - Writings - Columbia University, "Bacon and the Art Science Rift", 1958 (Folder 5.19)
  - Writings - Columbia University, "Equipment and an Architecture for the Twentieth Century", circa 1956 (Folder 5.20)
  - Writings - Columbia University, "Planning for Mechanical Equipment in the Contemporary House", circa 1956 (Folder 5.21)
  - Writings - Columbia University papers, circa 1949 (Folder 5.22)
  - Writings - "Closing the Housing Gap," draft, 1969 (Folder 5.23)
  - Writings - "Fair Housing and Urban Affairs," drafts, undated (Folder 5.24)
  - Writings - "The Liberal Arts Are Essential," clipping, undated (Folder 5.25)
  - Writings - Miscellaneous, 1947-1952 (Folder 5.26)
  - Writings - Miscellaneous, architecture and housing, circa 1960s (Folder 11.1)
  - Writings - Miscellaneous, architecture and housing, circa 1967-1968 (Folder 5.27)
  - Writings - Miscellaneous, personal, 1950s (Folder 5.28)
  - Writings - Miscellaneous, personal, 1954-1955 (Folder 5.29)
  - Writings - "The Multiple Dwelling Called "Habitat 67", 1967 Nov (Folder 5.30)
  - Writings - "New Processes in Architecture", undated (Folder 5.31)
  - Writings - "Notes on the Design of Housing in Connection With the Work of the National Commission on Urban Problems", undated (Folder 5.32)